

@

FMPaci88@gmail.com



5500, Mendoza, Argentina Argentina



https://fmpaci.github.io/



www.linkedin.com/in/fpaci/

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science: System Engineer

UADE, Argentina, Expected in December 2033 Status: Up to 3rd year

Industrial Computing Technician

I.T.U. (Instituto Tecnológico Universitario), Mendoza, Argentina

High School Diploma

ETIEC N° 4-003

Status: Electric technician

LANGUAGES

Spanish

Bilingual or Proficient (C2)

English

Upper intermediate (B2)

FEDERICO MARTÍN PACI

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Self-motivated Data Engineer with +5 years of experience in warehouse data management an development. Collaborates effectively with multi-functional roles to identify and leverage areas for improvement in data systems. Bringing comprehensive understanding of warehouse operations and documentation needs.

Currently studying best practices of DAMA organization to get better performance of data models, also data governance and metadata management.

SKILLS

- SQL Expertise on different engines
- ETL Development
- Python scripting
- Data Modeling
- Data Warehousing

- Cloud Computing
- Problem Solving
- Agile Methodologies
- Performance Tuning
- Data Migration

WORK HISTORY

January 2022 - Current

Frubana - Data Engineer, Remote

- Collaborated on ETL (Extract, Transform, Load) tasks, maintaining data integrity and verifying pipeline stability. Techs: Airflow, AWS Glue, and Python
- Develop Python dags and lambda to gather information from different sources, such as S3, API, goggle sheets
- Evaluated various tools, technologies, and best practices for potential adoption in company''s data engineering processes.
- Generate insights and dashboards with Metabase, Superset, Redash and Looker
- Administer users connections and permissions on Metabase, Superset, Redash, and redshift
- Monitor and control data warehouse and data lake performance, keep track of redshift queue, help clients with query tuning
- Keep track of customers' tickets and issues.

August 2021 - Current

Coderhouse - SQL Professor, Online

- Demonstrated strong interpersonal and communication skills, resulting in clear subject matter discussion with students.
- Meet with teams members to discuss different approaches, lessons and future learning objectives.
- Encouraged class discussions by building discussions into lessons, actively soliciting input, asking open-ended questions and using techniques to track student participation.
- Used different technology to engage students in achieving learning outcomes.
- Researched and selected course texts and supplemental learning materials.

May 2021 - October 2021

Eldar - Data Engineer, Remote

- Database Migration project, from DB2 to MySQL
- Design MySQL DDL based on current DB2 database
- Generate ETL process for development stage, in order to test cases and changes
- Suggest changes on data warehouse model, to reduce impact on extraction step.

May 2018 - May 2021

BBVA - Data Engineer, CABA, Argentina

- Develop ETL process, data modeling, and data pipelines in different tools such as SSIS SQL Server Integration Services, Teradata SQL, IPC PowerCenter
- Develop end-to-end process or solutions, from gathering user requirements, creating documents and developing SQL codes and couch final users
- Query tuning and database performance analysis
- Python development with Google Apis
- Coach coworkers in data warehouse model, SQL queries, and help them to solve performance issues
- Project and improvements proposed: Scoring of email integrating different sources, reducing wasted emails attempts in 38%
- Developed process to fix problems on clients' product activation, improving client satisfaction, reducing to 0 complaints with these problems
- Developed CRM-like application in excel, with connection to different data sources to reduce time consuming tasks
- Developed process to pay different gifts to clients and avoid conflicts between commercial campaigns.

May 2017 - May 2018

Centro Construcciones S.A. - Functional Administrator of Softland ERP, CABA, Argentina

- T-SQL Development, stored procedure, views, functions, and maintenance plans
- Administrations of user profiles and security parameters
- Document new process, create user manuals, flow charts.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Languages and expertise:

- Python
- SQL
- Data Warehousing
- Data Modeling
- DAMA Methodology

Frameworks:

- Airflow
- AWS
- Glue
- Spark
- SSIS
- SQL Server
- Teradata
- Redshift